原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译     千只鹤飞过波千鸟  tong大梨
翻译     VioletCheng  屯栗子
校对     屯栗子
时间轴     西·查
后期     渔夫
总监     屯栗子
辛普森一家
第三十一季  第五集
让路
Make way!
阿奎塔兹水上乐园
五部获大奖纪录片的拍摄对象
准备嗨起来  孩子们
Get ready for fun, kids.
从防晒霜开始嗨
Fun that begins with sunblock.
来嘛  阿麦
Come on, Maggie.
你不会想长大变成爷爷吧
You don't want to grow up to look like Grampa.
我无法看着动物被这样虐待
Ugh, I can't enjoy seeing animals treated like this.
海象敲敲敲
每天都被困在方玻璃后面
It must be horrible spending every day
一定非常恐怖
trapped behind a pane of glass.
售票处
确实不美妙
It ain't great.
宝贝  他们要是不开心
Sweetie, if they're so unhappy,
干嘛摇尾巴呢
why are they wagging their tails?
-鱼就是这样游泳的  -我说它们很开心
- That's how fish swim. - Well, I say they're happy.
企鹅葬礼会在12点  2点  4点举行
Penguin funerals at 12:00, 2:00 and 4:00.
来见见
你真可耻
虎鲸
虎鲸被称为顶级掠食者
The killer whale is called an apex predator
因为没有什么东西可以把它吃掉
because there's nothing that can eat it.
没有什么东西可以把它吃掉  真的吗
Nothing that can eat it, eh?
天皇特选寿司
不要  不要
No. No.
画风好诡异
This just got weird.
现在是我们的明星午饭时间啦
And now for our biggest star, it's lunchtime.
我需要一个小孩子
I need a small child out here.
你去吧  开胃小吃
You get on out there, Hors D'oeuvre.
别担心朋友们  我好几年前就失去了手臂
No worries, folks. I lost my arm years ago.
我们可以回家了吗
Can we please go home?
这个快乐的地方快把我弄哭了
This "fun" place is about to make me cry.
侯默  你带着阿麦散散步
Homer, why don't you take Maggie for a stroll
我们去看看那边的美人鱼
and we'll check out that mermaid over there.
这尾巴真的太假了
Oh, that tail is so fake.
史密瑟斯  我们可以溅湿
Smithers, can we splash the people
-在高级餐厅吃饭的人吗  -如你所愿先生
- dining at that fine restaurant? - As you wish, sir.
我超爱周日
I love Sunday fun.
知道吗宝贝  我一直想要一艘船
You know, sweetie, I always wanted a boat,
但我爸根本买不起
but my dad could never afford one.
30年前
*坐在海湾码头上*
*Sitting on the dock of the bay*
*什么学也不用上*
*Missing all my school today*
*坐等变蠢*
*Getting dumb...*
别吹口哨了
Knock off that whistling.
男人在沉默中才能享受
Men have good times in silence.
爸比  我们会有船吗
Daddy, will we ever get a boat?
逗我呢
Are you kidding?
我们连鱼饵都买不起
We couldn't even afford worms.
我欠你的
别哭了
Aw, don't cry.
来点苏格兰"喝了感觉会变好"饮料
Have some Scottish feel-good juice.
苏格兰威士忌
好吧
Okay.
来吧  喝了它
Come on. Drink up.
照今天来看  我是个好父亲
By the standards of the day, I'm a great father.
心满意足摩托艇
正在打结
爸爸的好船
船不错吧  我卖船的
Nice boat, huh? I sell boats.
想要一艘吗
Wish you could have one?
想要  但我从没有过一艘船
Yeah, but I'll never own a boat.
就是个梦  就像坐直一样
It's just a dream, like doing a sit-up.
别这么肯定
Don't be so sure.
我不知道你做什么工作的  但我呢
I don't know what you do for a living, but me?
我从事的是梦想职业
I'm in the dream business.
有些事情很可疑号
待售
我以为你卖船的  讲话打打草稿吧骗子
I thought you sold boats. Make up your mind, liar.
我这么做可能会有麻烦
Now I could get in big trouble for doing this,
但如果你以这个价格买船
but if you buy this boat now for the listed price,
我就送你一顶货真价实的船长帽
I'll throw in this genuine captain's hat.
别告诉我经理
Don't tell my manager.
你觉得我是白痴吗
What do you think I am, an idiot?
这顶帽子都不能调节大小
This hat isn't even adjustable.
-它是均码的  -成交
- It's one-size-fits-all. - Deal.
等等  我老婆会杀了我的
Wha-- No, wait, my wife will kill me.
当你老婆在日落的时候喝着玛格丽塔
You think your wife's gonna kill you
海洋上吹来的风轻柔的拂过她的秀发
when she's sipping margaritas as the sun sets,
你觉得你老婆还会杀了你吗
her hair blowing softly in the ocean breeze?
她的头发不会被拂过  风吹过的时候会有怪声
Her hair doesn't blow. It kind of clangs.
听着  随便问哪个理财顾问
Look, ask any financial planner and they'll tell you
他们都会告诉你买一艘船
that getting a boat is a better investment
比离婚或者开一家书店更适合投资
than getting a divorce or opening a bookstore.
再送我个东西我就买了
One more thing and I'm convinced.
我再送你一枚已经不存在的游艇俱乐部的徽章
I'll give you this little pin from a defunct yacht club.
成交
Sold.
这个钩子是什么东西
Hey, uh, what's this little hook thing on it?
那是个锚  你会成为一个优秀的游艇驾驶者
That's an anchor. You're gonna be a fine yachtsman.
我的天  你的背鳍塌了
Oh, my God, your dorsal fin has collapsed.
看见了吗  她没有足够空间游泳
Don't you see? She doesn't have enough space to swim.
这家伙真够大
That thing is huge.
这家公园残忍毫无人道
This park is cruel and inhumane.
清空水缸  拔掉插头
Empty the tanks. Pull the plug!
我会回来的  你无法让我沉默
I'll be back. You can't silence me.
好可爱呀
I-- aw. So cute.
又被一家游乐园丢出去了
Thrown out of another amusement park.
-把我带上  -没有你的安全带
- Take me with you. - Not enough seat belts.
酒吧
*你拿一个醉了的销售员怎么办*
*What do you do with a drunken salesman?*
*他回家找老婆*
*He goes home to his wife.*
终于卖掉了那个旧游艇
Finally moved that old cabin cruiser.
没人可以像你一样一眼认出傻比
No one spots a sucker like you.
我猜猜  胖子一个  还有中年危机
Let me guess. overweight guy, midlife crisis?
胖到你都不知道
The kind of fat where you don't even know
他们到底几岁
how old they are.
-你今天怎么样  -妙极了
- How was your day? - Beautiful.
我把按摩浴缸卖给有个进来打电话的人
Sold a Jacuzzi to someone who came in to use the phone.
你用浸渍附赠品勾搭他了吗
Did you gouge him on the dipping attachment?
全部卖完外加三千美金
Wholesale plus three grand.
快过来抱抱
You get over here.
给我一个提议
Make me an offer.
光滑
Smooth.
巴仔  我需要你的帮助
Bart, I need your help...
走开
Go away.
-是恶作剧哦  -你需要什么
- ...with a prank. - Oh, what do you need?
辣酱  牛心  火蚁
Hot sauce? Cow heart? Fire ants?
火蚁
他们不见了
They're gone.
火蚁是怎么逃出纸袋的
How could fire ants get out of a paper bag?
感谢主  让这些火蚁进入我的鼻子
Thank you, Lord, for these fire ants entering my nose,
啃咬我的大脑  检验我的信仰
biting my brain, testing my faith.
但是我会
But I will...
去他的  杀虫喷雾呢
Damn it, where's the spray?
阿奎塔兹水上乐园
谢谢你帮我们放生这条鲸鱼  威利
Thanks for helping us free that whale, Willie.
不谢  现在穿上伪装
Aye. Now, to put on me camouflage.
哥们  你真的很了解这个地方
Man, you really know this place.
我夏天在这工作
I work here in the summer.
不像你们这些孩子  鱼不会取笑我
Unlike you children, the fish don't make fun of me.
就算你们比我聪明
Just 'cause you're cuter than me
也不意味着你们比我强
don't mean you're better than me.
你们压根都不是鱼
You're not even a fish!
虎鲸水箱控制面板
让我来猜猜  这些就是虎鲸水箱的控制面板
Unless I miss me guess, these are the orca tank controls.
这人真厉害
This guy's good.
我们打开出口  她就能直接回到海里了
We'll open the seawater gate and she'll go straight in the ocean.
我觉得这是向左拧开
Uh, I believe it's lefty loosey.
这个国家所有的东西都是反的是错的
Everything in this country is backwards and wrong.
假年华游轮
谢天谢地  有下船的出口了
Thank God. A way off the ship.
我们做到了  我们放生了一只被捕的动物
We did it. We set a captive animal free.
挺酷的  对吧  巴仔
Pretty cool, huh, Bart?
你看看它有多开心
Look how happy that thing is.
丽莎  这是一种全新的感受
Lis, this is a new feeling.
我们帮助一只鲸鱼获得自由  现在我感觉很棒
We helped a whale be free and now I feel wonderful.
你想说的是  利他主义
What you're searching for is "altruism."
这叫做报应
And that's called karma.
你开心吗  威利
Are you happy, Willie?
我表演给你看  风笛
I'll show you. Air bagpipes.
好了  我要把眼罩拿掉了
Okay, I'm going to take the blindfold off.
不要问问题  不要探寻答案
Don't ask questions. Don't probe for answers.
我就假装不知道我们在码头上
I'll just pretend I don't know we're on a dock
靠着水边
next to the water.
看看我们在哪  靠着水边的码头
Look where we are. A dock next to the water.
有些事很可疑号
你今天还租了船
You got a boat for the day.
你带啤酒和三明治了吗
Did you bring beer and sandwiches?
何不打开这个看看
Why don't you open that?
马姬  啤酒和三明治在这里
Hey, Midge, got your beer and sandwiches right here.
阿麦  来坐到爸爸腿上开大船船
Come on, Maggie, get on Daddy's wap and take the wheel.
对啦  油门推到最大
That's right, maximum thwottle.
油门推到最大
Maximum thwottle.
你打滑啦  对就是你
Ooh, you're hydwopwaning. Yes, you are.
88岁了  一直都没学会游泳
88 years old and never learned to swim.
有些事情很可疑号
真是个美好的一天  老侯
What a wonderful day, Homie.
就像住在沙发上面那幅画里面
It's like we're living in the painting over our couch.
我们的婚姻从未像这样好
Our marriage has never been better.
是时候拿来冒个险了
Time to risk it all.
好了  猜猜这艘船是谁的
Okay, guess whose boat this is.
希望不是约翰尼·德普的
I hope it's not Johnny Depp's.
他已经有太多财务上的麻烦了
He's already in so much financial trouble.
坐稳了  宝贝  这是我们的
Brace yourself, baby. It's ours.
你买的这艘船
You bought this boat?
不  我们买的这艘船
No. We bought this boat.
你只是没发现
You just weren't aware.
-你知道吗  没关系  -你疯了吗
- You know what? It's okay. - Are you nuts?
你买到了全家可以一起享受的东西
You went out and got something the whole family could enjoy.
-咱们也奢侈一回  -我的天  马姬
- Let's live a little. - Oh, my God, Marge.
你怎么了
What's happened to you?
我承认  你让我筋疲力尽了
I admit it. You've worn me down.
你就是我闪闪发光的小宝石
You're my little polished gem.
你觉得怎么样  爸爸
What do you think, Dad?
你做到了  儿子  你真的做到了
Oh, you did it, son. You actually did it.
你在船坞找到了停车位
You found a parking spot at the marina.
-我从来没  -不  爸爸  我买了艘船
- Oh, I never... - No, Dad. I got a boat.
-上去  -好的  我  等等
- Get on. - Oh, sure. I-- Wait a minute.
你是要杀了我把我扔下海吗
You're gonna kill me and dump me overboard.
好吧  这是我的遗嘱
Well, fine. Here's my will.
遗嘱
每个人都能分到
侯默除外
别闹了
Oh, come on now,
我不会杀你的
I'm not gonna kill you.
因为你是个懒蛋
That's 'cause you're a lazy bum.
好了  来抱一个
Now, come on, give me a hug.
-船不错  -我是船主
- Nice boat. - I'm the owner.
非常好  我必须要告诉你  她有点坏了
Very nice. I must tell you, she's running a little rough.
我们不都是吗
Aren't we all?
不错
Good one.
听着  我是机械师
Listen, uh, I'm a mechanic,
我觉得你会需要我的帮助
and I think you're going to need my help.
你的船旧了  它现在需要维修
Your boat is used, and it needs repairs now.
为什么是现在
Why now?
它正在下沉
It's sinking.
苗浩斯  原来我沉迷于利他主义
So, Milhouse, it turns out I'm addicted to altruism.
只有放生一只动物我才会开心
I'm not gonna be happy till I set another animal free.
如果我想和丽莎一起出去玩  我就和丽莎去玩
If I wanted to hang out with Lisa, I'd hang out with Lisa.
不  你不能
No, you wouldn't.
现在我不能再放生鱼了
Now I can't free another fish
因为他们加强了水上乐园的安保
because they've increased security at the water park.
太棒了  我有手电筒了
This is great. I got a flashlight,
阿奎塔兹水上乐园商店
对讲机  一大串钥匙
walkie-talkie, big old ring of keys.
但是我发现了别的可以去放生
But I found something else we can set free.
认识一下大猩猩罗罗
Meet LoLo the gorilla.
强壮  聪慧
Powerful, intelligent.
她能比划出五个单词
She can sign five words.
朋友  敌人  杀戮
"Friend," "enemy," "kill,"
伏特加  还有  宋飞
"vodka" and "Seinfeld."
你知道她想要出来的
You know she wants out.
为了保密  剩下的我就用猪猪拉丁语说了
Now for security, I'll say the rest in Pig Latin.
[猪猪拉丁语]
Ee-way, ill-way, oh-gay, oh-tay, ee-thay, oo-zay.
我们要放到易贝上卖吗
We're going on eBay?
[猪猪拉丁语]
Ay-yay arumba-cay.
春田核电站
-你好  -你是坐着的吗
- Yello. - Are you sitting down?
当然了
Of course.
我修好了你的船  给你报个价
Fixed your boat. Here's the total.
别说我没提醒你
Don't say I didn't warn you.
还有希望  那就是  找人分摊你的花销
There is one hope: share your expenses.
把你的朋友一起拉进黑洞
Pull your friends into the black hole with you.
好的  先生  你现在应该消失了
Yes, sir. You're supposed to disappear now.
我会的  但是我得再收一百块
Yeah, I will, but that's another hundred.
-你好  侯默  -你怎么了
- Hey, Homer. - What's the problem?
我感觉很糟糕  就是很糟糕
I feel terrible, just terrible.
是吗  怎么啦
Oh, yeah? Why's that?
因为我一直在向你们
Because I have been withholding
隐瞒一个绝佳的机会
an incredible opportunity from you guys.
我很抱歉  我得走了
My apologies. Got to go.
我好像听到了"等等  等等"
Did I hear, "Wait, wait"?
-没有  -我们没说
- No. - We're good.
好吧  因为那个机会真的非常  非常棒
Okay, 'cause it's really, really incredible.
再见  我走了  真的走了
See you. Leaving now. On my way.
最后的机会  拜拜
Last chance. Buh-bye.
机会镜头
你好
Yello.
好吧  我认输  那个机会是什么
Okay, I'll bite. What's the opportunity?
我说不好  莱尼
I don't know, Lenny.
我是说  我需要一个很有热情的人
I mean, I need someone with genuine enthusiasm.
-了解了  晚...  -等等  等等  等等
- Understood. Have a good ni... - Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
你想跟我上同一艘船吗
Do you want to go in on a boat with me?
我们平摊花销  使用时间一人一半
We share expenses, we split the time.
你如果同意的话  就继续正常呼吸
If you agree, continue breathing normally.
我不知道
I don't know.
我听说共用一条船会毁掉友情
I heard that sharing boats can ruin friendships.
好吧  最好知会卡尔一声  因为他已经加入了
Well, somebody better tell Carl 'cause he is in.
等等  我不想落单  我也要加入
Wait, I don't want to be left out. I'm in!
太好了  你能让卡尔接电话吗
Glad to hear it. Could you put Carl on?
我们带来了大学时用过的音响
We brought our old college stereo.
我们要让水上的每个人都知道
Let's let everyone in the water know
某些风云人物正在肆意狂欢
some big shots are having a wild time.
Bachman-Turner Overdrive 《Takin' Care of Business》
*我就喜欢整天什么都不做*
*I love to work at nothing all day*
*还会照顾好生意*
*And I'll be taking care of business*
*每一天*
*Every day*
*照顾好生意*
*Taking care of business*
*用各种方法*
*Every way*
B.T.O.: Bachman-Turner Overdrive  加拿大70年代摇滚乐队
那些鱼有超棒的B.T.O.的音乐听了
Yeah, those fish are hearing some awesome B.T.O. Right now.
亲爱的  要不你来推一下油门杆吧
Why don't you take the throttle, dear.
我感觉到了  我感觉到力量了
Oh, I feel it! I feel the power.
我以为我们只是在随意约会
You know, I thought we were just dating casually.
并不会有什么结果  不过现在  你愿意娶我吗
It wasn't going anywhere. But now, will you marry me?
我  我可没拒绝你
I, uh... This is not a no!
*照顾好生意*
*Taking care of business*
*每一天*
*Every day*
春田动物园
猩猩馆
好了  我知道了
Okay, I've got it.
她不知道她背后有一条长长的藤蔓
What she doesn't know is there's an overgrown vine behind her
她可以顺着爬出去  就自由了
where she can climb up to freedom.
我们得有一个人进去做给她看
One of us has to get in there and show her how to do it,
但是谁进去呢
but which one?
我有跟你说过我对猩猩毛过敏吧
Uh, did I ever mention that I'm allergic to gorilla fur?
见鬼  这是少有的我不过敏的东西
Dang! The one thing I'm not allergic to.
知道吗  我还以为这次巴仔会去的
You know, this time I really thought Bart was gonna do it.
-下次我来  -我知道你会的  哥们
- I'll do it next time. - I know you will, buddy.
我们人性化对待动物
我们有麻烦了
We got a problem.
是两个麻烦
Two problems.
原来这就是在一个有爱的家庭里的感觉
So this is what it's like to be in a loving family.
等这玩意儿闭嘴了  我们就吃了它
你好
Hello?
丽莎  利他主义太害人了
Lis, altruism sucks.
你个白痴
You idiot.
你放生了一条鱼  因为鱼可以在海洋中生存
You set a fish free because it has an ocean to swim in.
如果你放走了一只大猩猩
If you set a gorilla free,
它会逃到城市里  然后会被杀掉的
it goes into the city and it gets killed.
"大猩猩的逃生之路"
"The Great Esc-Ape"?
Esc[退出]-Ape[猿]: 逃跑
一只大猩猩从春田动物园神秘逃跑
A gorilla mysteriously freed from the Springfield Zoo
疯猿罗罗
正在城市中造成破坏
is wreaking havoc all over town.
警方一如既往地无用
The police, as always, are useless.
通话中
才不是呢  肯特  我们已经找到大猩猩了
Not true, Kent. We've located the gorilla.
他在一家商店的牌子顶上  牌子上写着
He's on the top of a store next to a sign reading,
"你会为我们的折扣发狂的"
"You'll Go Ape For Our Bargains."
Ape  有猿也有狂热的意思
你会为我们的折扣发狂的
平躺商店
好吧  我觉得那是个气球  警长
Uh, yeah, I think that's a balloon, Chief.
证明给我看
Prove it.
开心了吗  阿卢
Happy, Lou?
你打爆了一个气球
You just shot a balloon.
有一艘船真是太好了
I love boat ownership.
每个周末都在抛光铜制把手
Spending every weekend polishing brass.
我感觉我就像拉里·埃里森
I feel like Larry Ellison.
Larry Ellison  甲骨文公司总裁
我把浓缩咖啡机固定在了常平架上
I had the espresso maker mounted on gimbals,
这样大浪袭来时
so when the big waves hit,
就不会弄坏我们的卡布奇诺上面的奶泡
they won't ruin the foam art on our cappuccino.
奶泡莱尼  你是我的英雄
Foam Lenny, you're my hero.
这些人是谁
Hey, who are all these people?
我可能不小心多卖出了几个股份
I, uh, may have sold some extra shares,
这些人恐怕都是船的共同拥有者了
so I'm afraid these are all co-owners.
拥有者就是我  我就是拥有者
Co-owner I be, says me. Yarr.
达夫曼想给他的新继子留个好印象
Duffman wants to impress his new stepkids.
你觉得怎么样  凯尔
What do you think, Kyle?
我爸爸是喝你们家的酒喝死的
My father died from drinking your product.
那我们还有很长的路要走
We have a lot to work on. Oh, yeah!
这些人都是共同拥有者吗  猫女士也是
All these people are co-owners? Even Cat Lady?
现在她摇身一变为双体船女士
Now she's Catamaran Lady.
人太多了  我动不了
There's too many people, I can't move.
好了  解开缆绳
Okay, cast off.
我的卡布奇诺奶泡
Hey, my cappuccino head.
至少我可以游到岸边
Well, at least I can swim to shore.
天哪  这也太难了
Eh, eh, this is, this is too hard.
等等  我可以站起来
Hey! Hey, I can stand!
不行  实在太难了
Eh, no, it's just too hard.
春田小学
或许音乐能让她平静下来
Perhaps music will calm her down.
一  八  七  七  车给孩子们
One, eight, seven, seven, cars for kids.
会有许可回执的
西摩·史金纳著
我的剧本
My screenplay!
罗罗  罗罗
LoLo. LoLo!
朋友  朋友
"Friend." "Friend."
天惹  我不小心比划成魔鬼了
Oh, no, I accidentally signed "fiend."
听着  我会帮你找到安全的地方
Look, I'll help you find safety.
我得说服你我是你的朋友  怎么操作
I just have to convince you I'm your friend. How?
怎么操作
How?
《宋飞正传》
Seinfeld.
邮差[剧中配角]
Newman.
如果你能更轻一点就好了
If this was just a little bit looser,
简直就是世界上最美妙的事情了
it would be the best thing in the world.
先生  我想退回船只
Sir, I would like to return my boat
请给我全额退款
for a full refund.
真抱歉  或许詹姆斯·卡梅隆
Oh, I'm sorry. Perhaps James Cameron
对你这艘快沉的破船感兴趣
would take an interest in your sunken ship,
但我收完钱工作就结束了
but my responsibility ended at ka-ching.
你卖给我的是垃圾[有柠檬意]
You sold me a lemon.
大家喜欢柠檬  对声带有好处
People like lemons. They're good for your voice.
你这油嘴滑舌的  谁会不买你的账呢
With your smooth talk, you could convince anyone of anything.
你喜欢我的翻领吗  想买这件夹克吗
You like my lapels? You want to buy the jacket?
-是的  -50块
- Yes. - 50 bucks.
请原谅一下
Now if you'll excuse me,
我还在忙着用自行车轮胎走私冰毒呢
I'm also in another business smuggling meth inside bicycle tires.
谢谢你给我免费的自行车
Thanks for the free bike.
明天到墨西哥就行了
Just get it to Mexico by tomorrow.
丽莎  你在做什么
Lisa, what are you doing?
我跟爸爸在卧室里
Um, I'm in my bedroom with Dad.
真可爱
Oh, that's sweet.
小心点
Watch it!
老侯  我告诉过你别那么做了
Homie, I told you to stop doing that.
乌歌
猩猩圣殿
你们把自己的大猩猩带来这里
Y'all bring your gorilla here.
我们会教它骑马  射击
We'll teach him to ride and shoot,
很快就要猩球崛起了
and soon it'll be a Planet of the Apes.
哎呦
Whoops.
不要
No.
在天合国  天才猿合众国
Here at U.T.A., United Talented Apes,
我们会把猩猩的毛刮掉
we'll shave your gorilla
让它做布鲁斯·威利斯的替身
and make him a body double for Bruce Willis,
如果它能够乖巧点的话
and if he behaves even a little,
就可以成为布鲁斯·威利斯了
he could become Bruce Willis.
下一个  天哪  天哪
Next. Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
太完美了  你会接收我的猩猩吗
You're perfect. Will you take my ape?
宾夕法尼亚州
猩猩自然保护区
古道尔博士  你救了罗罗我真的感激不尽
Dr. Goodall, I can't thank you enough for saving LoLo.
罗罗  这是它被囚禁时起的名字
LoLo. That's what they called her in captivity,
但是我给它起了个新名字
but I've given her a new name,
配得上这样神奇生物的名字  波波
one worthy of such magnificent creature, PoPo.
我能不能跟你说  你一直是我的英雄
And may I just tell you, you've always been my hero.
谢谢  但我很好奇
Thank you. But I wonder,
你跟多少女性科学家说她们是你的英雄了
how many female scientists have you told they're your hero?
你这个领域吗  只有三个人
In your field? Um, only three.
好吧  棒极了  我们会好好照顾波波的
Oh, well. Good enough. We'll take fine care of PoPo.
-回见  -等等  回来
- See you soon. - Wait. Come back.
带我走吧  我就想要你这样的生活
Take me with you. I want a life exactly like yours.
还有成百上千人也这么想
Well, so do hundreds of others,
但是你可能是那个幸运之人
but still, you might get lucky
如果你真的非常努力工作  拿到博士学位的话
if you work really hard and get a doctorate.
你能给我奖学金吗
Would you give me a scholarship?
不行  你得像我一样存钱
No, you'd have to save up, like I did.
哪怕有一点点机会你会要我吗
Then there's a slight chance you'll have me?
只有一点点  但别放弃
Well, very slight, but don't give up.
这是我听过的最鼓励人的话了
That is the most encouraging thing I have ever heard.
丽莎  谢谢帮我纠正我好心办的坏事
Lis, thanks for undoing the damage of my good deed.
我很高兴你逐渐明白了
I'm glad you've come to understand
利他主义的重点
the importance of altruism.
利他主义最棒了
Altruism rocks!
好比你放生的时候  放生物把其他物种都毁了
Like when you let something go and it smashes everything.
接下来我想对犀牛进行利他主义
Next, I want to altruism a rhino.
接着是对一个用铁锤做手的机器人
Then I'm gonna altruism a robot with sledgehammers for hands.
有时候我想坐下来
Sometimes I just want to sit back
看看这个世界上的利他主义
and watch the whole world altruism.
看呀  猩猩们从你父亲那里找到了
Look, the gorillas have picked up some new habits
新的栖息地
from your father.
没错  但侯默也学到了很酷的猩猩动作
Yeah, but Homer picked up some cool gorilla moves, too.
老谋子酒吧
我绝不...
Well, l, I never.
好了好了  我知道你们很生气
Okay, okay, I know you're mad,
但因为我们人数众多
but because there are so many of us,
每个人只会损失很小的一部分
we each just lost a little.
我只是想说
And I just want to say,
你们的下半辈子
for the rest of your life,
你们会明白自己
you'll know that you're just
跟拥有自己船的人一样好
as good as someone who owns a boat
因为你们也拥有过5分钟的船
because you owned a boat for five minutes.
你的确给了我们一些可以抵消损失的东西
Well, you did give us something for our money:
美好的回忆
great memories.
看看日本人给我漂流回来什么了
And look what someone in Japan sent back to me.
为侯默三呼万岁
Three cheers for Homer.
万岁万岁
Hip, hip, hooray!
《奶泡莱尼》
Foam Lenny on FOX,
周五八点  尽在福克斯
Fridays at 8:00,
因为我们没别的节目了
because we've got nothing else.